Hello everyone, welcome back to our SQL tutorial series. So today we are diving into the
Fire clause SQL
The component of filtering data. So first of all simply define the SQL wire clause. So the
Fire clause allows us to specify the condition when we're driving data from the table in the SQL
It's like a filter that helps us to narrow down
our result. Okay, so let's explore how it works with some example. So first of all, I can hear the basic wire clause
So in this example, I can select for the record from the table based in this place. We condition. Okay
So first of all, I can just type select and
star prompt and
Then type here the Easter
Employees. Okay, and next step here. I can just apply this is where
For the department. Okay
So this is the department is equal to
So here I can use for the department of IT. Okay, so now I can
Use this from the employees table where the department column is equal to IT department and
this query will be turned all the employees for all to in the IT department. Okay, so here now select and
create you can see here the one employee and
the employee name is Johan and
it is
30 and department for IT and the department for one employee is working for the IT department. Okay
So I hope you understand it and the next step here. I can create using for the comparison operator
And the wire clause also allows to use the comparison operator to specify the condition. Okay
Now, just go for here and first of all create the select this from the employees
Now here I define for the age. Okay, so you move for the department and now inside page column and
Here I can apply for
Age is greater than 30. Okay
So now this example you're driving the reports from the employee stable
What the age is greater than 30 and this query will
With employees older than 30 years. Okay, so now just see and select and
Execute you can see here not
Or get at it. Okay, here you can insert another
Define phone here
Create for so first like 25. Okay
Then execute
And you can see here it will start put for greater than 25 and they are state for the call
We're leaving all records from the
employee stable. I hope you understand it and
Next step here. I can create
Supposedly I can just create the another
Combining condition. Okay
So you can also combine for multiple condition using for the logical
like for
Or a part okay, so now just go here and first of all here
I can create suppose like the department. Okay, so define for the department column is equal to
Suppose here I can create for the department of
Here I can define for the
Department this is the seven. Okay, and now here I can use the
End operator and create for the age column
It's greater than 30. Okay
Now just check and here I can define the 30 and here set for the ages
28, okay
So now and these
record from the employees and the table for both the department in the IT
Sorry, and age is greater than 28 and
A school return the employees who are older than 30 and working like
This department. Okay, so now select here execute. You can say here
Define for here, so
Just like here define for 26. Okay
and then execute and you can see here
The employee side is two and then first on the Johan and age is 28
And perfectly defined the department of civil. Okay, so perfectly replied for the record from the
Impress table. Okay, so next is the here create another example. Suppose here creating for using the
Will part so now create and first of all here. I can type the first name
so the
Will for we use where the type for here first name
Okay, so this one
This is the first name column and then we move here
This statement and the type for first name is the like operator and now here simply use for the word of J
And there create for the module, okay
And this example retrieving records from the employees table or the first name column starting with the letter of J
And the module required is a match any sequence of character following the character of J. Okay
So now just select and execute now you can see here
All columns are
Row starting for the character of J. Okay
so you can see here
So here the session is completely done and there you have it. It's an overview of the
Where clause in the SQL would some practical example and hope you find this tutorial helpful
So stay tuned for more SQL
Keep some tricks. So thank you for watching and happy coding